Lady Euphyllia.
May I carry that one, as well?
Yes, please do.
The Magical Revolution
of the Reincarnated Princess and the Genius Young Lady
Oh, right... The villa...
Lady Euphyllia, good morning.
May I come in?
Ilia?
Thank you for coming every morning.
You may come in.
Pardon me.
Did you sleep well last night?
Yes, quite well.
Have you grown accustomed to this place?
Yes, and the move has proceeded smoothly.
A lot has happened, but thanks to Miss Anis,
I'm not seen as a mere curiosity.
That is wonderful.
I hate to say this immediately
after things have settled down,
but you've been summoned
to the castle this afternoon.
Yes, I know. For questioning, right?
May I ask you to accompany me?
There are things I'd like to bring back.
Very well.
Um, where is Miss Anis?
She flew off on her broom at dawn.
She made a grand show of it in secret.
A grand show in secret?
What a strange way to describe it.
That is how things always are.
What is that noise?!
The alert system that Miss Anis invented.
It sounds when someone
suspicious enters the grounds
and sends a notification to
Miss Anis, but this time...
Ow...
I blew it again.
Oh, good morning, Euphie!
Good morning.
Did you have breakfast already?
Come help me experiment, then!
Experiment?
Yep! Remember what I said?
I'm gonna make a special
magic tool just for you!
The first thing we're
experimenting with is this!
Ta-da-da-da! A Mana Blade!
Here, try it out!
U-Um, what am I supposed to do with...
Just run some mana through it.
O-Okay...
This is very impressive.
Uh-huh! It's a magic sword
whose blade is activated by mana!
The balance of spirit stones
is really delicate, though,
so forget about close-quarters combat.
It's unfortunately a bit weak
against physical impact,
It's extremely portable and
effective in magic combat.
but it's super strong against magic!
It's real handy for getting rid of magic!
If it can also function as a wand,
it'll be quite useful.
Its strength and durability depend
on how you set it up...
That's it! Way to go, Euphie!
Great looks, great smarts,
and a great personality!
R-Right...
Okay, let's try this one next!
Are you sure this is safe?
It's shaking so much!
I won't die, right?!
You'll be just fine! I've got you!
I won't let go of the back!
You mean that? No matter what?
You'd better promise!
Don't let go under any circumstances!
Yep, no matter what! I promise!
Royals don't lie!
I'm... flying?
This is what it feels like to fly?
Miss Anis, is this righ—
Euphie!
Are you okay?! I'm sorry!
That was an accident!
I-I mean it!
I've already verified all
the safety measures myself,
so I thought you'd be fine!
So, um... So, well...
I-I'm sorry.
Pardon my rudeness.
No, it's totally fine!
No, it really isn't.
You are a princess.
But I'm not next in line or anything.
That doesn't matter.
Besides, I am your assistant now.
I must show you proper respect.
You really don't need
to treat this so formally.
I just want you to enjoy playing right now.
Playing?
Well, until you get used to it, I mean!
You can just treat this like play!
And if you're gonna study,
you should have fun doing it.
Devices like this have a
playful element to them, too.
If you're too tense with them,
they'll break in no time.
Still, we can't have you
playing around too much.
Lady Euphyllia, it is time.
Please get ready to go.
Right.
Well, Miss Anis, if you'll excuse me.
You have to go somewhere?
I've been summoned by His Majesty.
Oh... Okay. See you later, then.
Has Miss Anis always been like that?
Most certainly not.
Long ago, she was even more reckless.
Her absurdity, idiocy,
and insanity were on full display.
You have quite a difficult job yourself.
I'm all right.
It's a maid's job to be at
the mercy of her mistress.
No... it's a perk, in fact.
A perk? Really?
Yes, a perk.
I guess this is all still a bit beyond me.
I'm sure.
If you don't like it, it will be best
for you both if you simply say so.
Oh, no, it's not that I don't like it.
How unusual.
I had no idea there was anyone commendable
enough to find that princess favorable.
Well, I wouldn't say I find her favorable...
The truth is that I simply don't understand.
I do believe she's a good person, but...
She's just... so far from me.
For crying out loud... I don't even
want to look at this testimony.
I was present during the questioning,
and he only said the same
thing over and over.
I see.
I ordered Algard to remain in his chambers,
but I suppose nothing has changed.
He insists on choosing his own path,
meaning he will not be bound to an
engagement his father chose for him.
For some random person on
the street, that's fine,
but we are a royal family.
We have certain responsibilities!
It's not just Prince Algard.
The other boys said very similar things.
You could try to put more pressure
on them, but it would be difficult.
They're all the sons of
very powerful people.
You can expect unwanted interference.
Yes... and Count Chartreuse, the Secretary
of Magic, is of particular concern.
I'm sure he wants to protect his son, but...
The count is a conservative leader.
Since I am supported by the reformists,
he sees me as an enemy,
so he strongly resists me.
Facing off with a conservative, eh?
It all makes my stomach hurt.
Enter.
I see.
So you had very little interaction
with the daughter of Baron Cyan?
Correct.
I once offered her some advice,
but no more than that.
Hmm...
I can't see any problem with your
behavior as a betrothed noble lady.
Any noble should understand that.
It doesn't sit right with me to conclude
that the prince and lady overreacted
simply because they were maddened by love.
Do you have any other ideas
or realizations to share?
Though I'm sure you aren't keen
to recall that moment...
Everyone seemed firmly convinced
of their own righteousness.
Even when he insulted me,
I felt he was doing it
not out of malice, but simply
to follow his own conviction.
Those who are intoxicated by
their own sense of righteousness
do tend to become blind to what
happens around them...
I'm sorry, but would you mind
giving me some time?
If I come across anything, I'll contact you.
Of course. In that case...
What is this?
The key to the forbidden library.
I was borrowing it for
lessons on being a queen.
I see.
If you want, you're welcome
to hold on to it.
I no longer have the right.
I return it to you.
You were going through all that for us...
I'm sorry.
N-No, Your Majesty! Please don't say that!
But...
The prince's heart simply had no room
for me in the first place.
But I am not deeply wounded by that fact.
It's as if I feel nothing...
Like everything has completely dried up.
You have more than fulfilled your role.
You need not think about what comes next.
There is nothing more you need to do.
Then I'll say hello to everyone here
who was kind to me, and return home.
Don't you think you could have
phrased that differently?
You never say quite enough.
Don't I?
Being a father is difficult.
You can say that again.
Lady Euphyllia...
Are you all well?
You all did so much for me.
Lady Euphyllia!
Had I known you were coming,
I would have come to collect you.
I'm sorry to take up your time.
I wanted to say hello to everyone.
You honor us.
Have you lost some weight?
Yes, just a bit. I'm sorry.
No, no. You have nothing to apologize for.
Oh, that's right.
My dress fittings will
no longer be necessary.
Your body shape never changed
a bit, Lady Euphyllia.
Really?
Of course.
That sounds wonderful.
The princess eats and drinks too much,
and she always runs amok in her dresses,
so I have to mend them over and over.
And she hates corsets and bustiers.
She is truly a free spirit.
I can picture that.
Perhaps you are just as
free now, Lady Euphyllia.
You don't need to wear
dresses or corsets anymore.
There is nothing to tie you down any longer.
You're right.
Nothing... Nothing at all.
Euphie!
Miss Anis? What are you wearing?
Oh, sorry! I only slept
for about two hours...
Actually, more like one hour...
Yeah, I only slept for an hour.
In fact, it's more like
I didn't sleep at all!
Sorry I kept you waiting!
Is this...
Yes! The blade is an alloy containing spirit
stones, making it a conductor for mana!
But we should probably test out
its mana conductivity first.
If it works, we can add different
attributes to the blade!
Then it'll be a luxury item
that'll help you with using magic!
In other words...
I finished your special magic tool!
My own... special magic tool?
Yeah! Now let's—
Princess, please change your clothes first.
Okay! Go on and try it out!
You can just use that tree as a target.
What? A-Are you sure?
Uh-huh!
Amazing... It's as though
it's already a part of me.
Fireball!
Wow, that was awesome!
Well? Well? What do you think?
It's an incredible item.
I'm so glad to hear it!
Okay, now test it out as a magic sword, too!
Blade, assume form...
Water Blade!
Wow! It really is a sword!
This is... How shall I put it?
Very interesting.
It's still true.
Euphie's magic is so beautiful.
Thank you, Miss Anis.
Don't mention it.
It was really fun thinking about
what would suit you best.
Does it... really suit me?
Sure it does.
It all started with the concept
of something made just for you.
It has to suit you.
I thought of a name for it, too.
A name?
Yeah.
Arc-en-Ciel.
Arc... en Ciel?
It means "rainbow."
It has lots of different magic attributes,
and lots of colors.
It's perfect for you.
Rainbow colors... are perfect for me?
Thank you. It's a lovely name.
Really? I'm glad.
U-Um...
It really is a perfect match.
I've always thought...
that you were as pretty as a rainbow.
You really are... so pretty, it's unfair...
Miss Anis?
What am I going to do with you?
No one has ever rested
their head on my lap before.
I envy you, Miss Anis.
If I could be even the least
little bit like you...
Episode Three
The Rainbow Magic Sword
of Longing and Reminiscence
Episode Four
The Princess and the Lost Child
Announce Their Decision